{
  "age": 59,
  "background": "Master Upholsterer",
  "directory": "content/state-house/district-38c",
  "district": "38c",
  "dob": "3/9/1959",
  "education": "Master Universal mechanical artist.",
  "filename": "ed-tinus.md",
  "full-name": "Ed Tinus",
  "general-only": true,
  "jurisdiction": "Worcester County",
  "last-name": "Tinus",
  "party": "Republican",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Do you support the findings of the Commission on Innovation and Excellence in Education? Are you committed to funding associated reforms, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "The Ed App Through true transparency will allow every voter in the State of Maryland to read information on this commission. From the comfort of their own home the voters can interact with the Ed App to network / educate ,  and vote . This campaign will engage the voters with the political process. Thus taking the special interest groups out  of the politicians pockets. We have the technology today for a Popular Vote Revolution. Citzens and Government working together.",
      "shortname": "Kirwan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is Maryland’s transportation spending appropriately balanced between roads and transit? Does the state have the resources to meet its transportation needs? With the cancellation of the Red Line and the advent of BaltimoreLink, is the Baltimore region adequately served by transit?",
      "answer": "No region is adequately served with there transit needs. Here in District 38C our infrastructure and evacuation routes are non-existent.  In the case of emergency we will be bumper to bumper.",
      "shortname": "Transportation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the legalization of recreational marijuana?",
      "answer": "Yes  I have applied to the IRS for Non-profit status 501 - C3 for a District 38 Recreational Marijuana Dispensary. The 38 RMD 's proceeds from the W12 organization will provide funding of first responders, Schools, property tax assistance, and the Worcester County Building fund. This will be the first federal recognition for the sale of marijuana.",
      "shortname": "Marijuana"
    },
    {
      "question": "At a time when the federal government’s commitment to Chesapeake Bay restoration is questionable, what new steps should Maryland take to protect this resource?",
      "answer": "My passion is to clean the Patapsco River basis. I have designed a caisson method of sludge removal that will not have the tax payers cover the expense. No high impact dredging that will release more toxins then already being leached into our National Treasure. I have scuba dove of Fort McHenry and the chemical smelling   sludge is over three foot thick. Aberdeen Proving Grounds has been rumored for along time of barrels of mustard gasses and other agents being buried that leach into the water shed. Thus bay grasses and wild life are poisoned. We must investigate this rumor.",
      "shortname": "Chesapeake Bay"
    },
    {
      "question": "What steps should Maryland take to ensure the broadest possible access to affordable health care?",
      "answer": "Stop following federal government guide lines. Open a competitive  insurance system with a rewards in place for healthy enrollees.",
      "shortname": "Health Care"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role should the state play in helping Baltimore address violent crime?",
      "answer": "Mandatory sentencing.",
      "shortname": "Crime"
    },
    {
      "question": "How would you characterize Maryland’s business climate? What can the state do to foster the creation of more family-supporting jobs?",
      "answer": "Build a Eastern Shore beltway system , a 707 Northern Bay Bridge , Restore the Chesapeake. To be specific create large projects that will create secure employment  for generations to come. A $15.00 per hour working wage. With out placing the burden on the small business owners. The welfare assistance program can finance the wage increase for recipients. At the current rate a recipient of welfare , financially fares better then the minimum wage of today. That one receives approx. $22.00 per 40 hour work week , not working? At the minimum rate today plus a subsidiary of $7.00 from assistance less the $22.00 saves $15.00 . Opening a wage increase for most minimum wage employees.",
      "shortname": "Business Climate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the creation of a non-partisan, independent body to draw legislative and congressional district maps after each census?",
      "answer": "Yes both parties are only looking for their own interests.",
      "shortname": "Redistricting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does the Law Enforcement Officers Bill of Rights adequately balance protections for police and the public? Should it be changed, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "No",
      "shortname": "LEOBR"
    },
    {
      "question": "What strategy would you adopt to address the opioid addiction and overdose crisis?",
      "answer": "Stricter penalties for dealers. Mandatory with draw for users.",
      "shortname": "Opioids"
    },
    {
      "question": "What if anything should the state do to address income inequality?",
      "answer": "See question 13",
      "shortname": "Income inequality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do the state’s Public Information Act and open meetings laws adequately ensure Marylanders’ ability to exercise oversight of the government?",
      "answer": "This campaign is the first in this nation that will utilize the voters smart devises to be engaged through education . The Ed App is a transparent vehicle that will drive the voters to Annapolis from the comfort of their own homes. Allowing the voters to vote on Bills such as HB 1302 . A Bill that infringes search and seizure,  gun ownership rights. Bill such as these can and must be put to a Popular Vote. No representative should bear the burden of nor has the authority to vote on Constitutional abridgments. Only We The People can amend the Maryland and U.S. Constitution.",
      "shortname": "Transparency"
    }
  ],
  "race": "state-house",
  "residence": "Whaleyville",
  "social-fb": "Friends-of-Ed-Tinus-324453870984394",
  "survey-response": true,
  "title": "Ed Tinus",
  "web": "http://www.united-us.org"
}
